(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-30T09:28:31.740892",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
遥々起きた朝は
Waking up so early in the morning,
なんだかいつもより眠くて
For some reason I'm sleepier than usual.
昨日の夜ずっとマンガを読んでたら眠れなくってさ
Staying up all night reading manga left me unable to sleep.
今頃そっちはどこで何してるかななんて
Wondering what you might be up to over there right now,
考えてたら心がふわっと軽くなるんだ
Makes my heart feel a little lighter.
これは内緒なんだけど昨日読んだマンガの主人公に君がちょっと似てたんだよ
It's a secret, but you looked a bit like the hero in the manga I read yesterday.
ねぇ お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 一緒に
Hey, let's have lunch, lunch, lunch together,
お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 食べよう
Lunch, lunch, lunch, lunch!
ちょっとだけ同じ気持ち共有したくて
Wanting to share just a little of the same feeling,
そう お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 だけでも
Yeah, even if it's just for lunch,
全然特別なことじゃなくても
Even if it's nothing special at all,
いつもの君でいいんだよ
You can just be your usual self.
一緒に食べよう
Let's eat together.
決してリア充とは言えない地味な日々だけど
Even though these plain days could hardly be called fulfilling,
なぜだろう 最近は少しキラキラなんだ
For some reason, lately they feel a bit sparkly.
どんなに直前に嫌なことあっても
No matter how much unpleasant stuff happens right before,
君に会えると思うとによにゃけちゃってさ
Thinking about meeting you makes me grin from ear to ear.
ねぇ お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 一緒に
Hey, let's have lunch, lunch, lunch together,
お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 食べよう
Lunch, lunch, lunch, lunch!
ひとりよりきっと楽しくなるから
It'll surely be more fun than eating alone,
そう お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 だけでも
Yeah, even if it's just for lunch,
全然特別なことじゃなくても
Even if it's nothing special at all,
いつもの君でいいんだよ
You can just be your usual self.
一緒に食べよう
Let's eat together.
ねぇ お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 一緒に
Hey, let's have lunch, lunch, lunch together,
お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 お昼 食べよう
Lunch, lunch, lunch, lunch!
こんなことしかないから変なこと考えないでよ
There's nothing else to this, so don't go thinking weird things!
まあ別にいいけど知ってるかな
Well, whatever is fine, but do you know?
君がくれる...
The warmth you give me...
ランラララ ランラララ ランラララ lunch with me
Lalalalala lalalalala lalalalala lunch with me
遥か起きた朝は
Waking up far too early,
なんだかいつもより眠くて
somehow I'm sleepier than usual.
昨日の夜、ずっとマンガを読んでたら
Last night, I kept reading manga,
眠れなくなってさ
so I couldn't sleep.
今頃、そっち人はどこで何してるかな?
I wonder what you're up to right now.
なんて考えてたらココロがフワッと軽くなるんだ
Thinking about that makes my heart feel so light.
これはナイショなんだけど
This is a secret, but...
昨日読んだマンガの主人公にキミがちょっと似てたんだよ
you looked a bit like the hero in yesterday's manga.
ねぇ お昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 一緒に (昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 昼)
Hey, noon, noon, noon, noon, noon, noon together—
食べよう
let's eat!
ちょっとだけおんなじ気持ち共有したくて
I wanted to share that little feeling with you,
そうお昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 だけでも (全然特別なこと じゃ) なくても
so even if it's just noon (even if it's nothing special at all),
いつものキミでいいんだよ 一緒に食べよう
you're always great just as you are. Let's eat together!
ランラララ ランラララ ランラララ lunch with me
Lalalalala lalalalala lalalalala lunch with me
決してリア充とは言えない地味な日々だけど
Even though I can't call my plain days those of a social butterfly,
なぜだろう最近は少しキラキラなんだ
why is it that lately they feel a bit sparkly?
どんなに直前にイヤなことあってもキミに会えると考えるとニヤけちゃってさ
No matter how awful things were right before, just thinking about seeing you makes me grin.
ねぇ お昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 一緒に (昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 昼) 食べよう
Hey, noon, noon, noon, noon, noon, noon—let's have lunch together!
一人よりきっと楽しくなるから
Because it's bound to be more fun than being alone,
そう お昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 だけだし (全然特別なこと じゃ) ないから
so even if it's just noon (since it's nothing special at all),
変なこと考えないでよ? まぁ別にいいけどさ
don't think weird things, okay? Well, whatever is fine, though.
知ってるかな? キミがくれる言葉一つ一つ
Did you know? Every single word you give me
嬉しくなったり楽しくなったり不思議なパワーを感じるってこと
makes me happy, makes me joyful, and I feel this mysterious power.
ねぇ お昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 一緒に (昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 昼) 食べよう
Hey, noon, noon, noon, noon, noon, noon—let's have lunch together!
ちょっとだけおんなじ気持ち共有したくて
I wanted to share that little feeling with you,
そう お昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 昼 だけでも (全然特別なこと じゃ) なくても
so even if it's just noon (even if it's nothing special at all),
いつでもキミがいいんだよ 一緒に食べよう
I always want you. Let's eat together!
ランラララ ランラララ lunch with me
Lalalalala lalalalala lunch with me
はーい、というわけで1曲目ねねのオリジナル曲「ランチタイムを」お聴きいただきました。
All right! That was the first song, my original track "Lunchtime."
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ちょっとお水飲んでくるわ。
I'm gonna go grab some water real quick.
すごいんだよ、ランチタイム使う
It's amazing, using Lunchtime—
消費エネルギーつうのはもう ものすごいもんよ。
the energy consumption is just off the charts.
はーい、というわけで今日はですね、こちらのねねファーストアニバーサリーとネブラボ1周年のタグで、
All right, so today, under the tags for Nene's 1st anniversary and Nebulabo's 1st anniversary,
よかったらいっぱい、スクショとか感想とか募集してます。いっぱい呟いてね。
if you'd like, please post lots of screenshots and impressions! Tweet away, everyone.
見て見て、これゲームセンターのステージに移動してきました。
Look, look! I've moved to the game center stage.
どう? かわいいでしょ?
How is it? Cute, right?
ちょっと、息1つ整えないと次の曲に行けないよ。
Hold on, I gotta catch my breath before the next song.
みんなといえばあれどうだった? プレミアム公開、ミッサミュージックをみんなで歌いました。
By the way, how was that? For the premiere, we all sang "Missa Music" together!
なんとね、動画を作ってくれてるのはあののりプロのあのわらべちゃんが作ってくれました。
And you know what? The person who made the video was none other than Warabe-chan from Noripro!
忙しい中本当に、ありがとう!
Thank you so much despite your busy schedule!
みんなね、それ分かってね、もう1回見てくれよな。
Everyone, knowing that, please go watch it again, okay?
はい、というわけでねねの息がなんとなく落ち着いてきましたので、
All right, so Nene's breathing has calmed down a bit,
えー、次の曲に移ろうと思ったんだけど、
um, I thought about moving on to the next song,
もうちょっと休憩しても大丈夫だよって言われたから、
but they told me it's okay to rest a little longer,
もう1回水を飲んでから次の曲に移動します。
so I'm gonna drink some more water before moving to the next song.
今回ね、あの、
This time, um...
フリー入れが4日間くらいしか練習できなくて、もうちょっと1曲目からめちゃめちゃ不安だったんだけど、
I only had about 4 days to practice the free entry, so I was super nervous from the very first song,
なんとかうまくいったわ。よかったよかった。
but somehow it went well. Phew, I'm so glad!
はい、じゃあ次の曲に行こうかな。次の曲はこのゲームセンターにぴったりのキャラクターの曲を歌いたいと思います。
All right, shall we go to the next song? For the next one, I'd like to sing a character song that fits this game center perfectly.
かくしん的☆めたまるふぉ〜ぜっ！
Kakushinteki☆Metamorphose!
もっと もっと 楽しめよう
Let's enjoy it more and more!
みんなに気付かれないように
So that nobody notices us,
秘密のヒモ解いちゃおう
let's untie our secret string!
お気に入りのフードかぶり
Wearing my favorite hoodie,
今日も今日とてゴロゴロして
I'm lounging around again today,
大好物のポテチを手にして
with my favorite potato chips in hand,
パソコンにらめっこよ
glaring at my computer.
立てば芍薬 座れば牡丹 歩く姿は百合の花
Peony when standing, tree peony when sitting, lily when walking—
誰もが羨む完璧JK
the perfect high school girl everyone envies!
ほら 玄関開けたら変身ださくっ
Look, once you open the front door, it's transformation time—tackiness,
さようなら
farewell!
U・M・R！ハイ！ U・M・R！ハイ！
U-M-R! Hai! U-M-R! Hai!
UMAじゃないよ うまる
I'm not a UMA, I'm Umaru!
いつだって全身全霊遊び倒せ
Now's the time to give it my all, playing with 100% effort!
もっと もっと楽しめよ乙女
More and more, enjoy yourself, maiden!
みんなに気づかれないように
So that no one notices you,
いざ行け！干物妹ライフ
Go on! NEET lifestyle!
お気に入りのフードかぶり
Putting on my favorite hood,
今日も今日とてゴロゴロして
Lazying around today just like every other day,
大好物のポテチを手に入れた
With my favorite potato chips in hand,
パソコンと睨めっこしよう
Playing a game of staring contest with the PC!
立てば芍薬 座れば牡丹
Slender like a peony, sitting like a peony,
歩く姿は百合の花
Walking like a lily flower,
誰もが羨望完璧JK
Envy of everyone, the perfect high school girl!
ほら玄関くぐったら変身だ！
Now, open the front door and transform!
さあごうたしようぜ
Time to be a slacker!
いつだって「食う・寝る・遊ぶ」の3連コンボ
Always living by the triple combo of "eat, sleep, play"!
ずーっとずーっとゲームは友達
Always, games are my best friends!
お兄ちゃんは厳しいけれど きっときっと許してくれるの
Onii-chan might be strict, but I'm sure, sure he'll forgive me!
わがままほうだいは「大好き」の裏返し
All this selfishness is just a sign of how much I love you!
立てば2頭身 座ればまんまる
Slender like 2 heads tall, sitting round and round,
歩く姿はちんちくりん 誰でも癒せる愛敬マスコット！？
Walking like a shorty, anyone's adorable healing mascot!?
さあ限界超えるまでパーティナイト！ 宴の始まりだぁ！
Now, until we break past our limits, party in night! The banquet is beginning!
清楚で優しい女の子演じてみても お兄ちゃんだけは騙せない
Even if I try to act like a graceful and elegant girl, I can't fool Onii-chan!
嫌われたくないもん 素直に言えない「ありがとう」
I don't want to be hated, a simple "thank you" I can't say honestly,
態度でしめそう …だぁ！前言撤回！
Ending up with a stubborn attitude... ...Daa! Retracting that statement!
あぁもういいいいじゃん！
Ah, whatever is fine!
お兄ちゃんなんて知らない！ 何っすって！？
I don't even care about Onii-chan! What did you say?!
一心同体ふたりでヒットだってだってそれがきょうだいでしょう？
Inseparable, the two of us are one, because that's what siblings are, right?
一蓮托生ふたりきりの運命共同体
Sharing the same fate in this two-person cooperative squad!
今日だって自由奔放笑い飛ばせ
Today too, live a free-spirited and smiling life!
もっともっと楽しんだもん勝ち
Winning means having more and more fun!
天真爛漫スマイルでぎゅっとぎゅっと心を掴んじゃうの
With a pure and innocent smile, grabbing your heart tight!
やりたいほうだいは信頼の裏返し？
Could this selfish behavior be a sign of trust?
U・M・R！ハイ！ U・M・R！ハイ！
U-M-R! Hai! U-M-R! Hai!
UMAじゃないよ うまる
I'm not a UMA, I'm Umaru!
U・M・R！ハイ！ U・M・R！ハイ！
U-M-R! Hai! U-M-R! Hai!
UMAじゃないよ うまる
I'm not a UMA, I'm Umaru!
外では猫をかぶり
Outside, I wear a cat mask,
今日も明日も演じるのです
acting the part today and tomorrow,
大好評の笑顔を武器に
Using my popular smile as a weapon,
友達にばれないように
So my friends won't find out!
立てば2頭身 座ればまんまる
Slender like 2 heads tall, sitting round and round,
歩く姿はちんちくりん
Walking like a shorty,
誰でも癒せる愛敬マスコット！？
anyone's adorable healing mascot!?
さあ限界超えるまでパーティナイト！
Now, until we break past our limits, party in night!
宴の始まりだぁ！
The banquet is beginning!
清楚で優しい女の子演じてみても
Even if I try to act like a graceful and elegant girl,
お兄ちゃんだけは騙せない
I can't fool Onii-chan,
嫌われたくないもん
because I don't want to be hated!
素直に言えない「ありがとう」
A simple "thank you" I can't say honestly,
態度でしめそう …だぁ！
Ending up with a stubborn attitude... ...Daa!
前言撤回！
Retracting that statement!
あぁもういいいいじゃん！
Ah, whatever is fine!
お兄ちゃんなんて知らない！
I don't even care about Onii-chan!
何っすって！？
What did you say?!
一心同体ふたりでヒットだってだってそれがきょうだいでしょう？
Inseparable, the two of us are one, because that's what siblings are, right?
一蓮托生ふたりきりの運命共同体
Sharing the same fate in this two-person cooperative squad!
はい、おしまい！
Alright, that's it!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
えー、かくしん的☆めたまるふぉ～ぜっ！をお聞きいただきました！
You've listened to "Kakushinteki☆Metamaruphose!"!
あの、スタッフさん、なんかマイクがガビガビ言ってるから、もしよければチェックしていただけると幸いです。
Um, staff, my mic sounds all staticky, so I'd appreciate it if you could check it.
なんか、ブツッ、ブツッて言ってます。
It's making popping sounds like "pop, pop."
ねぇの耳がおかしいのかな？
Is something wrong with Nene's ears?
ねぇの耳っぽぇ？ ねぇのイヤホンの問題っぽいかな？
Or does it sound like Nene's ears? Or maybe it's my earphones?
あ、みんなちょっとごめんね！ あ、じゃあ次じゃ次のステージに移っちゃおうかな。どうぞ！
Ah, everyone, sorry! Ah, then shall we move on to the next stage? Go ahead!
スタッフさん準備お願いします！
Staff, please get ready!
え、なんだろう？ げ、不鳴？
Eh, what is this? Unresponsive?
あ、なんにも聞こえなくなっちゃった！ あ、聞こえた。
Ah, I can't hear anything anymore! Oh, I can hear it.
げ、不鳴っぽい。まぁいっか、何かあったら止めよう。
Looks unresponsive. Oh well, if anything happens, I'll stop it.
はい、というわけで次はね、えーこれ、どこのステージか覚えてるみんな？
Alright, so next, um, does everyone remember where this stage is?
どろん、どろん、どろん、どろん。ラヴィアンの湖に遊びに来てみました！
Doron, doron, doron, doron. I came to visit Lamy's lake!
じゃ、ここに来たらさ、ね、絶対にやりたかったことがあるんだよ。
So when I came here, you know, there was something I definitely wanted to do.
ちょっとごめんね、雪民さん、先に謝っとこ。雪民さん、全世界の雪民さん、ごめんね。
Sorry, Yukimin, let me apologize in advance. Yukimin, Yukimins all over the world, I'm sorry.
あー、な、なんだろう、もっと何も聞こえなくなった。
Ah, wh-what's this, I can't hear anything again.
あ、なんか、なんだろうな。なんか雪っぽい。
Ah, it feels kind of snowy.
雪っぽい香りがする。この、
It smells like snow. This,
この柱とかラミィがなんかぎゅってしたらなんか匂いするわ。ねぇの手形つけとこ。
this pillar or Lamy, if she squeezes it, it smells like something. I'll leave Nene's handprint here.
はい、というわけで、ちょっと今ね、マイク見てもらってて、なんか大丈夫そうになった！よかった、よかった。
Alright, so, um, the staff just checked my mic, and it looks like it's okay now! Good, good.
ねぇ見て、ここに来るとね、ねぇめっちゃ幻想的じゃない？なんか！
Look at this, coming here makes Nene feel so fantastic, doesn't it?
うわ、やばくない、これ！
Wow, isn't this amazing!
映えちゃってるじゃん！ラミィさすがだな、すご！ねぇ、ねぇすら映える、この湖最高だ！
It's so photogenic! Lamy is truly amazing, wow! Even Nene looks photogenic, this lake is the best!
おっ いいじゃん
Oh, this is nice.
というわけでね、次はね、このとっても幻想的な空間にぴったりの曲を持ってきたので、
So, next up, I brought a song that fits this extremely fantastical space perfectly,
それを歌っていきたいと思います。
so I'd like to sing it.
よし、よいしょ。
Alright, heave-ho.
え、それでは次の曲聞いてください。「Sincerely」。
Well then, please listen to the next song, "Sincerely."
知らない言葉を 覚えていくたび
As I learn words I didn't know,
面影のなか 手を伸ばすの
I reach out into the shadows.
だけど一人では 分からない言葉もあるかもしれない
Though there may be words I don't understand alone,
さよならは苦くて
Goodbyes are bitter,
アイシテルは 遠くに匂いがした
And "I love you" had a distant scent.
例えようのない この想いは
This indescribable feeling
とても怖くて だけどとても愛おしくて
Is so frightening, yet so precious.
わたし なんで 泣いているんだろう
Why am I crying?
心になんて 答えられたらいい
How I wish my heart could give an answer.
言葉はいつでも 語るでもなくて
Words are not always meant to be spoken,
そこにあるばかり 募るばかり
They are simply there, ever growing.
わたしは あなたに 会いたくなる
I find myself wanting to see you.
きれいな言葉を 覚えていくたび
As I learn beautiful words,
自分のことが 嫌いになりそう
It feels like I'll grow to dislike myself.
だけど背を向けちゃ いけない言葉もあるかもしれない
But there may be words I cannot turn my back on.
かなしみは冷たく
Sadness is cold,
ありがとうは ぬくもりに色づく
And "thank you" is colored in warmth.
形のないもの 触れるたびに
Whenever I touch things without form,
あなたの声が 胸の奥で 響いているの
Your voice echoes deep within my chest.
書きかけてはやめた あて先のない手紙は
A letter with no addressee, which I started and stopped writing,
風に揺るる 届けたい人の街まで
Flutters in the wind, all the way to your town.
始まりの終わりを 伝えるために
To convey the end of a beginning,
生きること やめないこと
May you live on, never stopping,
あなたに 今日を 誇れるように
So that you can be proud of today.
わたし なんで 泣いているんだろう
Why am I crying?
心になんて 答えられたらいい
How I wish my heart could give an answer.
言葉はいつでも 語るでもなくて
Words are not always meant to be spoken,
そこにあるばかり 募るばかり
They are simply there, ever growing.
わたしは あなたに 会いたくなるよ
I find myself wanting to see you.
かなしみは冷たく
Sadness is cold,
ありがとうは ぬくもりに色づく
And "thank you" is colored in warmth.
形のないもの 触れるたびに
Whenever I touch things without form,
あなたの声が 胸の奥で 響いているの
Your voice echoes deep within my chest.
書きかけてはやめた あて先のない手紙は
A letter with no addressee, which I started and stopped writing,
風に揺るる 届けたい人の街まで
Flutters in the wind, all the way to your town.
始まりの終わりを 伝えるために
To convey the end of a beginning,
生きること やめないこと
May you live on, never stopping,
あなたに 今日を 誇れるように
So that you can be proud of today.
書きかけては やめた
What I started and stopped writing,
あて先のない 手紙は
That letter with no addressee
風に揺るる 届けたい人の街まで
Flutters in the wind, to the town of the one I want to reach.
始まりの終わりを 伝えるために
To convey the end of a beginning,
生きること やめないこと
To live on, never stopping,
あなたに 今日を 誇れるように
So you can be proud of today.
生きることを やめないことを
To live on, never stopping,
あなたに 今日を 誇れるように
So you can be proud of today.
わたし なんで 泣いているんだろう
Why am I crying?
心になんて 答えられたらいい
How I wish my heart could give an answer.
言葉はいつでも 語るでもなくて
Words are not always meant to be spoken,
そこにあるばかり 募るばかり
They are simply there, ever growing.
わたしは あなたに 会いたくなるよ
I find myself wanting to see you.
書きかけては やめた
What I started and stopped writing,
あて先のない 手紙は
That letter with no addressee
風に揺るる 届けたい人の街まで
Flutters in the wind, to the town of the one I want to reach.
始まりの終わりを 伝えるために
To convey the end of a beginning,
生きること やめないこと
To live on, never stopping,
あなたに 今日を 誇れるように
So you can be proud of today.
生きること やめないこと あなたに 今日を 誇れるように
To live on, never stopping, so you can be proud of today.
あなたに 会いたくなる...
I want to see you...
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
音声をお聞きいただきましたー！
You've just listened to the audio!
はいじゃあね あんまりここに長くせーとちょっと雪見さん 雪見さんがね
Yeah, we shouldn't linger here too long or Yukimiya-san will...
俺も俺もってなっちゃって急遽次のステージ行くわ ね！せーのっ！
start saying "me too!" So we're hastily heading to the next stage. Ready, go!
あーやっぱここが落ち着くわー
Ah, as expected, this place feels so relaxing~
よしちょっとお水飲むね
Alright, let me drink some water.
というわけで今えー新曲セーリィをお聞きいただいたんですけどどうでしたでしょうか？
So, we just listened to the new song "Sincerely," how was it?
ね、背景とぴったりだったでしょ？ ちょっとまだこの曲とっても難しかったから
It fit the background perfectly, right? This song was still really hard,
もっとなんか練習して もっといい感じに歌えるようになったらまた披露するね
so once I practice more and sing it better, I'll showcase it again.
ちょっとコメント読んじゃおう
Let's read some comments.
え、「ないとはおかえり実家のような安心感 最高 エモい はしゃがなくていいから ホームが一番」
Ah, "Naito, welcome back, home-like comfort, max emo, no need to get hyped, home is best."
え、ここでもはしゃげるが？ねえ。
Eh, you can get hyped here too? Hey.
うわああああああ！
Uwaaaaaah!
じゃあ次に行くの大変だから あんまり暴れられないよ
Well, since moving to the next one is tough, we can't go too wild.
浄化されただって？ ありがとう。え、良かったに合ってた？
"Purified"? Thank you. Eh, did it suit me well?
これ心の綺麗な人にしか見えない水だよ。見える？ 見える？
This is water only visible to people with pure hearts. Can you see it?
いやみんなに見えるからどうかな？
Well, everyone can see it, so I wonder?
じゃあね次の曲に行きたいと思うんですけど次の曲は
Well then, I'd like to move on to the next song, the next song is...
放送でねねがちょっと匂わせしたことあったかな？「名言」？名言だっけ？
Did Nene drop hints about it on stream before? "Famous quote"? Was it?
なんかの時に「もうほぼそれ答えじゃん」って言われたんだけど、その匂わせしてた曲を今日はなんと全編ね、オリジナルフリステでこうやらしていただいてるので
Someone said at some time, "That's basically the answer," but today for that teased song, we're doing the whole thing with original choreography,
思いっきりやっていきたいと思います！
so I'm gonna go all out and do it!
みんなも多分知ってると思う有名な曲を元気いっぱいやってくぞー！ってことで、次の曲聞いてください、「シル・ヴ・プレジデント」！
I'm sure you all know it, we're going to do this famous song with full energy! So please listen, "Sil V President"!
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない 消してあげる
Romance scandals won't get away, I'll make them disappear.
宣誓！ 私が大統領になったら 人の男にちょっかいかける女は島流しにします
Oath! When I become president, any woman messing with another man gets exiled!
宣誓！ 私が大統領になったら いやだねの友達だよって誤魔化す奴はヘソから電流を流します
Oath! When I become president, anyone who brushes it off saying "We're just friends!" gets electrocuted from their belly button!
だ・だ・だ・大胆不敵 セーセンショナル クローズアップ
D-D-D-Da-Da fearless, sensational close-up!
D, D, D, Don't cry やるぜ徹底的にリサーチだ
D, D, D, Don't cry, I'll thoroughly research!
大嫌い? しょうがない? クズは病気ね バイバイ・バイ
Hate it? Unavoidable? Scum is a disease, bye-bye-bye!
権力! 財産! 地位名声!! なにもないけど裁きたいでしょ?
Power! Property! Status, prestige!! You want to judge me for nothing, don't you?
だ・だ・だ・大統領になったらね まずは君を捕まえるね
When I become president, first I'll catch you!
濡れたタオルで 洗いさらえ吐かせるね
With a wet towel, I'll make you cough it all up!
誰ですか あの女
Who is that woman?
ダメですか そうですか
Is that bad? Is that so?
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない 消してあげる
Romance scandals won't get away, I'll make them disappear.
シル・ヴ・プレ・プレジデント
Sil-vu-pre-pre-president!
宣誓！ 私が大統領になったら ただの仕事の付き合いだよって言う奴は二度と働けなくしてやります
Oath! When I become president, anyone who says "It's just a business relationship" will never work again!
宣誓！ 以下略！ いや向こうが強引でさって言う男の口にはレジンを流し込んで固めてやります！
Oath! Abbreviation! If a guy says "Well, she was too pushy," I'll pour resin into his mouth and harden it!
み・み・み・密着 まるでドン・ファン気取り スキャンダラス
Close, close, close, close, like a Don Juan pretender, scandalous!
ま・ま・ま・末端価格 甲斐性なしのスコープね
Low-end price, a scope with no financial security!
愛はない? 理由じゃない 悪くないのね はいはいはい
No love? Not a reason, not bad, right? Yes, yes, yes!
軽薄! のうのう! いけしゃあしゃあ!!
Frivolous! Complacent! Shameless!!
なにないとかありえないでしょ?
Nothing like that is impossible, right?
だ・だ・だ・大統領になってもね 多分君は変わらないね
Even if I become president, you probably won't change!
ね知らっ知りと飛び降りて 乗り換え交わすのね
Playing dumb, jumping off and swapping around!
デートですか 今晩は
Is it a date? Good evening!
本気ですか そうですか
Are you serious? Is that so?
情熱とは不注意 微熱も消してしまいたい
Passion is carelessness, I want to extinguish even the slight fever!
だ・だ・だ・大統領になったらね マジで君を捕まえるね
When I become president, for real I'll catch you!
濡れたタオルで 洗いさらえ吐かせるね
With a wet towel, I'll make you cough it all up!
どこですか 今あんた
Where are you right now?
見っけちゃった ばれちゃった
Found you, got busted!
夜道にはご用心 さようなら代わりに銃声
Beware of the night, gunshots instead of goodbye!
シル・ヴ・プレ・プレジデント
Sil-vu-pre-pre-president!
軽薄・どうのこうの・いけしゃあしゃあ！ 何もないとかありえないでしょ？
Frivolous, this and that, shameless! Nothing like that is impossible, right?
だ・だ・だ・大統領になってもね 多分君は止まらないね
Even if I become president, you probably won't stop!
チラッとぼけて のらりくらりかわすのね
Playing dumb, dodging craftily!
デートですか 今晩は
Is it a date? Good evening!
見送りですか そうですか
Is it a send-off? Is that so?
情熱とは不注意 二列目も阻止してしまうたい
Passion is carelessness, I want to block even the second row!
だ・だ・だ・大統領になったらね マジで君を捕まえるね
When I become president, for real I'll catch you!
濡れたタオルで 洗いさらえ吐かせるね
With a wet towel, I'll make you cough it all up!
どこですか 今あんた
Where are you right now?
今あんた
Now, you...
見えちゃった バレちゃった
were seen, were found out...
道連れは今夜
Tonight you'll be my company
さよなら
Farewell...
代わりに銃声
Instead, a gunshot
シル・ヴ・プレプレプレジデント
Sil-vous-pre-pre-president!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
シルヴ、プレジデント、おきげいいただきましたぁ！
I received... your support for "Sil-vous President"!
大変だったこの曲は……ふう。
This song was so rough... Whew.
あの、長めに休憩取って大丈夫です。
Um, taking a long break is fine.
終わったね。あの、長めに休憩取っていいですか皆さん。
It's over. Um, can I take a long break, everyone?
ちょっとね、あの、今日はねこの方たちに何人か来ていただいてますので、ちょうどステージ上に来ていただきたいと思います。
Um today we have a few of these guys here with us,
so I'd like them to come up on stage.
それでは、それでは、ねっこのみんなー！
Well then, well then, everyone in Neko-no-minna!
あ、逆立ちで今日は来たのね。
Oh, you came doing a handstand today.
あ、浮いてるね、今日調子いいね！
Oh, you're floating, you're in great shape today!
かわいい、今日もかわいいよ。ちょっとねねが水の前にちょっとドアップで写っててね。
Cute, you're cute today too. Nene's up close
right in front of the water...
お、残り椅子だね。
Oh, it's a chair left over.
おいらは、茶色行こう茶色行こう。
Hey, let's go with brown, let's go with brown.
チーム・ネネ！
Team Nene!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much! Thank you!
これ、あれなのかな？
Is this... what is it?
この子はここにいたまま、次の曲に行けたりしますか？
Can this kid stay right here
and move on to the next song?
あ、本当？じゃあおれ、オレンジの子さ、ちょっといてもらおうかな次。寂しいから。
Oh really? Then, hey, the orange kid,
I might have you stay for the next one.
おいで、オレンジのこべ。今日は君が主役だ。
Come here, little orange one.
Today you're the star.
いや、寂しがりかよ！寂しがりか！おいで。
Man, you get lonely so easily!
So lonely! Come here.
イェーイ！イェーイ！よしよし。よしよしよしよし。
Yay! Yay! There, there.
Good boy, good boy.
さあ、シルヴプレジデントだったんだけど、みんなはどうだった？
Now, that was "Sil-vous President",
how was everyone?
どうだったどうだった？なんか、結構ね、あのネネの歌うの、リクエストありますかって聞いたときに、
How was it, how was it? When I asked
if there are any requests for Nene to sing,
あのこないだあげたグッバイ宣言と一緒くらい結構リクエストがあって、
there were quite a few requests around the same
as "Good-bye Declaration" I uploaded the other day,
あ、これはね、可愛い曲だし、あの、振り付けありでやりたいなと思って、撮っといたんだよ。みんなどうだった？
and I thought, "Ah, this is a cute song,
and I want to do it with choreography," so I filmed it.
ちょ、コメント見るね。あ、よかった？あ、よかった？
Let me check the comments.
Ah, was it good? Ah, was it good?
本当、奇跡的にね、今の1回だけ、あの、ダンスにそんな、あの、やばいミスがなくてね、とっても安心してるわ。
Really, miraculously, just this once,
there were no terrible mistakes in the dance, so I'm relieved.
さっき、やばかったマジでさっき。練習の時やばかったの。
It was so scary just now.
It was scary during practice.
白い子アンチみたいな動きしてたよ。
The white one was moving like an anti-fan.
え、何どうしたの？ねね、なんか、ちょっと言ってみろよ、なんか。
Eh, what, what's wrong?
Nene, say something, come on.
というわけで、ねねはですね、今日で、なんと1周年を迎えることができまして、
So, Nene has, today, somehow been able
to celebrate her 1st anniversary,
この1年の間にね、昨日も振り返りしてたんだけど、本当にたくさんのね、あの夢が叶えまして、こんなね、みんなたくさん見てくれる、このステージの中で歌って踊れることが本当に嬉しく思っています。
and over this past year, I looked back yesterday too,
so many dreams came true, and I'm truly so happy
to be able to sing and dance on this stage watched by you.
いつも準備をいっぱいしてくれてる、あの、今聞いてるであろうスタッフのみんなもありがとうございます。
Thank you to all the staff who are probably
listening now and always preparing so much for me.
はい、というわけで、2年目のねねもね、いっぱい目標を立てたんで、お、いいじゃん、これ可愛いじゃん！
Yes, so, Nene in her 2nd year has also set
lots of goals, oh, nice, this is cute!
ねねから葉っぱが生えた。2年目のねねねはね、もっと目が生えて、こいつがぐんぐんぐんぐん成長していくように、そんな感じになれるように頑張っていきたいと思います。
Leaves sprouted from Nene. In her 2nd year,
Nene will grow more sprouts, and I'll work hard
so that this little guy grows stronger and stronger.
で、みんなつぶやいてくれてる？これ。つぶやいて、ねねファーストアニバーサリー！ね、これプロポーズ発音したんだよ。
And everyone, are you tweeting? This.
Tweet it, "Nene First Anniversary!"
Hey, I pronounced this like a proposal.
ちょっと、ちょっとしゃべりっぱなしだと息が全然整わない。はじびちょう、あ、きょういい感じじゃん。
Phew, if I keep talking without stopping,
my breath doesn't settle at all. Hashibichou... ah, today's vibe is good.
今日、今日もビジュがいいね。
Today, my visuals are great again today.
ねぇの今日のカメラワークさ、今日すごい映りいいわ。あ
Today's camera work is amazing.
かわいい、かわいい、かわいい、かわいい。
Cute, cute, cute, cute, cute.
いしょっ。
There we go.
さてさてじゃあ、次の曲にいきたいと思います。
Well then, let's move on to the next song!
で、次の曲は、
And the next song is...
ねぇの今日見てる？ママ、
Nene's, you know, mama—
ねぇのママが好きな曲を1曲歌いたいと思います。
I'll sing one of Nene's mama's favorite songs!
じゃあ次はね、ちょっと雰囲気に合わせて、ねぇのこの夜のステージに行きたいと思うので、一緒にステージ軸を歪めたいと思います。
So next, to match the mood, let's align our axes for Nene's night stage!
というわけで、
So with that said...
カモン、ナイト！
Come on, night!
ちょっとダサかった、今の。
That was kind of awkward, just now.
もっとかっこいいのあったかな。
Is there a cooler way to do it?
さぁ夜になったのでね、じゃあ次の曲をね、聴いてもらいたいと思いますよ。
Now that it's nighttime, I hope you'll listen to the next song, too!
ちょっとねぇこ聴いてもらおうは、
Let's have Nene listen along—wait.
あ、この、この子いたままにします。
Ah, I'll leave this child right here.
はーい。
Right.
じゃあちょっと大根くんもね、バイバイン。
And Daikon-kun too, bye-bye!
めっちゃ吹っ飛ばんでいっちゃった。
He got blown away!
はい、じゃあ次の曲の準備をしたいと思います。
Right, then let's get ready for the next song.
はい、じゃあ次の曲いきます。
Right, let's go to the next song!
えっと、次はまた新鮮な曲を聴いていただきたいと思います。それでは皆さん聴いてください、未来へ！
Next, please listen to another new song. Everyone, please listen to it. To the future!
ほら 足元を見てごらん
Look closely at your feet,
これが あなたの歩む道
This is the path you walk on.
ほら 前を見てごらん
Look ahead of you,
それが あなたの未来
That is your future.
母がくれた たくさんの優しさ
Mother gave me so much kindness,
愛を抱いて 歩めと繰り返した
"Hold onto love and walk," she would repeat.
あの時は まだ 幼くて 意味など知らない
Back then I was still too young to understand the meaning,
そんな 私の手を握り 一緒に歩んできた
Holding my hand, we walked together.
夢はいつも 空高く あるから
Dreams are always high up in the sky,
届かなくて 怖いいね だけど 追い続けるの
Scary because we might not reach them, but I keep chasing them.
自分の ストーリーだからこそ 諦めたくない
Because it's my own story, I don't want to give up.
不安になると 手を握り 一緒に歩んできた
Whenever I felt uneasy, you held my hand and walked with me.
その優しさを 作時には嫌がり
That kindness sometimes annoyed me when I was writing,
離れた母へ 素直になれず
Unable to be honest with my distant mother.
ほら 足元を見てごらん
Look closely at your feet,
これが あなたの歩む道
This is the path you walk on.
ほら 前を見てごらん
Look ahead of you,
それが あなたの未来
That is your future.
未来へ 向かって ゆっくりと 歩いて行こう
Towards the future, let's walk slowly.
ごめん 憧れてた 追いかけてた
I’m sorry, I admired you and chased after you,
いつまでも其処にいたかった
I wanted to stay there forever.
完璧なあなた 嫌いになった
The perfect you became someone I disliked.
同じように愛貰って育ったのに
Even though we were raised with the same love,
いつからか差が開いていた
before I knew it, a gap had opened between us.
八つ当たりだったりしたかった
I wanted to just lash out at you.
ねえ Maybe
Hey, maybe
神様は試練与えた 強くなれと
God gave me trials, telling me to grow strong.
ウザい平等なんて嘘つき
"Annoying equality" is such a lie,
わかってるけど
even though I already know that.
可愛いとかモテたいとか
Wanting to be cute and popular,
諦めないの女の子だし
because I'm a girl who doesn't give up!
しおらしく（ハイ） 猫被り（ニャー）
Gracefully (Hi!), feigning innocence (Nya!)
オンリーワンだよ☆愛してね
I'm the only one! ♡ Make sure to love me.
生き方は無限にある
There are infinite ways to live life,
お父さんの大げさな言葉
those were my dad's exaggerated words.
いじらしく（ハイ） 猫被り（ニャー）
Lovingly (Hi!), feigning innocence (Nya!)
私らしく行こう
Let's go with my own way,
暇じゃない人生生きよう
living out this busy life to the fullest.
だって理想言えばキリがなくて
Because when you talk about ideals, there's no end to it,
無いもの全部欲しがって
wanting everything that I don't have.
鏡を見だって
When I looked in the mirror
ため息はぁ
and let out a sigh, "Haa..."
あなただって悩んでいた
I realized you were troubled too,
知らなかった
and I never knew.
みんなと同じだと知った
I found out you were just like everyone else.
ピント張った糸緩んでく
The tightly taut thread has loosened up.
運命日
The day of destiny—
神様は楽しんでる
God is having fun
予想できない人を
with unpredictable people.
私はそれ以上に楽しんでやるぜ
I'm gonna have even more fun than that!
勉強とかお仕事とか
Studying or working—
諦めないの女の子だし
because I'm a girl who doesn't give up!
ごめん 憧れてた
I’m sorry, I admired you
追いかけてた
and chased after you,
いつまでもそう でいたかった
I wanted to stay like that forever.
完璧なあなた嫌いになった
The perfect you became someone I disliked.
同じように愛貰って育ったのに
Even though we were raised with the same love,
いつからか差が開いていた
before I knew it, a gap had opened between us.
ヤツ当たりだってしたかったってね
I wanted to just lash out at you.
神様は試練
God gave me trials,
与えた強く慣れよと
telling me to grow strong.
歌い平穏なんて
"Peaceful singing"—
嘘つき 嘘つき わかってるけど
what a lie, even though I know that.
可愛いとか
Wanting to be cute
モテたいとか
or popular,
諦めないの女の子だし
because I'm a girl who doesn't give up!
ちゃっかりシワらしく
Smartly and gracefully
猫被り 男子ぶり
feigning innocence, acting like a boy—
お釣りはまだよ
my change is still yet to come.
愛してね 生き方は
Love me! There are infinite
無限にある 父親の
ways to live life, my dad's
大げさな言葉
exaggerated words.
ちゃっかりシワらしく
Smartly and gracefully
猫被り 私らしく
feigning innocence, going my own way—
いこう 気まちゃな人生
let's go live this capricious life.
だって理想を言えば キリがなくて
Because when you talk about ideals, there's no end to it,
無いもの全部 欲しがって
wanting everything that I don't have.
鏡を見だって ため息はぁ
When I looked in the mirror and let out a sigh...
あなただって 悩んでいた
I realized you were troubled too,
知らなかった
and I never knew.
みんなと同じだと知った
I found out you were just like everyone else.
ピント張った糸緩んでく
The tightly taut thread has loosened up.
運命日
The day of destiny—
神様は楽しんでる
God is having fun
予想できない人を
with unpredictable people.
私はそれ以上に楽しんでやるぜ
I'm gonna have even more fun than that!
弁当とか お仕事とか
Bento boxes or work—
諦めないの女の子だし
because I'm a girl who doesn't give up!
元気よく愛想よく 黙りはくらに
Energetically, sociably, keeping quiet...
ついてきて 愛されたぶん
Follow me! In return for the love you receive,
愛されるのお母さんがくれた
to be loved in return, mom gave me
アドバイス
her advice.
張り切ってミスしても
Enthusiastically, even if I make mistakes,
私らしくいこう
let's go with my own way.
胸張って生きる
Let's live proudly with our heads held high.
曝け出せば心叩かれてたんだ
When I bared my heart, it was beaten,
「好きに言ってろ」痛くない
"Say whatever you want," it doesn't hurt anymore.
神様は夢与えた 変わるために
God gave me dreams in order to change.
サンキューのっかってやるよ
"Thank you!" I'll ride along with it,
最後まで付き合ってもらうよ
and have you stay with me until the very end.
神様は夢与えた 変われるために
God gave me a dream so I could change,
サンキューの数稼ぐよ 最後まで付き合ってもらうよ
I'll rack up the thank yous,
so stay with me till the end!
雨はやんで傘を閉じた
The rain stopped and I closed my umbrella.
今まで見えてなかった景色 透明が放射して世界を照らした
Scenery I couldn't see before—
transparency radiated and lit up the world.
胸躍る かわいいとか持ってたいとか諦めないの女の子だし
My heart races—wanting to be cute,
not giving up because I'm a girl,
しおらしくね てっこかぶり ナンバーワンでしょ 愛してね
acting modest, putting on a front.
I'm number one, right? Love me!
生き方は不けんにある お父さんの大げさな言葉
Way of life is in freedom?
My dad's exaggerated words,
いちらしくね てっこかぶり 私らしくいこう 暇じゃない人生
acting like myself, putting on a front.
Let's live as ourselves, a busy life!
生きよう
Let's live!
ありがとうございましたー！ナンバーワンをお聞きいただきましたー！
Thank you very much!
You've just heard "Number One"!
というわけで次が最後の曲になってしまうんですけど、ステージを移動していきたいと思います！よっこらしょー！
So, the next song will be our last,
but I'd like to move to a different stage! Here we go!
はあ…… ちょっと水飲んだね
Phew... I drank a bit of water.
これはね、なんだろ、あの、見た目以上にすごい、消費エネルギーが高い。たかった！
This is... um, it takes way more energy
than it looks. That was tough!
というわけで、今もお伝えしたんですけど、次で最後の曲になります。
So, as I just mentioned,
the next song will be the last one.
え、これが終わりましたら、ねねからのお知らせが、えー、1個、2個、3個、3個かな？ありますので
And once this is over, Nene has announcements—
um, one, two, three... three of them?
というわけでこのステージなんだけど、これねねのさ、あの、桃の木の、この並木、並木通り？並木？
So about this stage, it's Nene's... um,
peach tree avenue, tree-lined path? Avenue?
このね、森に、あの、すごい、ぴったりのね、まだみんなには1回も、1回も、歌ったすらしたことない曲をね
and I want you all to listen to a song today
that fits this forest so well—never sung before.
すごいね、歌詞がねねとみんなと、そしてこの1周年……耳の、なんかゴミ全部取ってから聞いてね（笑）。
It's a song that fits Nene, everyone, this 1st anniversary,
so please clean the wax out of your ears first!
はい、というわけで、ちょ緊張するな。緊張するけど……すごくダンスが難しくて、この曲一番苦労したんだよ。
Yes, so... I'm a bit nervous. I'm nervous,
but the dance was super difficult for this song!
なんか、ちょっとね、イメージとしては……バルディナっぽい感じ、そういうなんか、おしとやかなねねをね、堪能してください。
Um, sort of, the image is like... something
like a ballerina, please enjoy that graceful Nene.
というわけでステージに着きます！お水飲みます！……それでは聴いてください、桃鈴ねねの曲、「モモノネ」！
So, we've arrived at the stage! I'm gonna drink water!
Please listen to Momosuzu Nene's song, "Momonone"!
いくつもの夢という花がこの惑星には咲いていたんだ
Flowers called dreams have been blooming
on this planet time and time again.
「自分もきっと」って憧れては思いきり葉を広げたんだ
Admiration made me think "I can do it too,"
and I spread my leaves to the fullest.
そう不安なときもいつも支えてくれていた根っこだからきっともっと大きくなる！
Even in uneasy times, the roots that always
supported me will surely grow even bigger!
思いは真っ直ぐ、伸びてゆけあの空に届くようにもう怖いものなんてない思いきっり咲かせるよ
Straightforward feelings, grow to reach that sky!
With nothing left to fear, I'll bloom!
自分という名の大きな花満開の桃の花
A giant flower named myself—
a fully blooming peach blossom.
いくつもの夢という花がつぼみのまま咲くのを待っている
Flowers called dreams are waiting
to bloom while still in bud.
いくつもの夢という花が
Flowers of countless dreams
この惑星には咲いていたんだ
were blooming on this planet.
「自分もきっと」って憧れては
Yearning, thinking, "I can surely do it too,"
思いきり葉を広げたんだ
I spread my leaves to the fullest.
そう不安なときも いつも支えてくれていた根っこ
Even in anxious times, the roots always supported me,
だからきっともっと 大きく なれる！
So I can surely grow even bigger!
想いは真っ直ぐ、伸びていけ
Feelings stretch straight ahead,
あの空に届くように
reaching up to that sky.
もう怖いものなんかない
With nothing more to fear,
めいっぱい咲かせるよ
I'll make it bloom in full,
自分という名の大きな花
A great flower called myself,
満開の桃の花
A peach blossom in full bloom.
いくつもの夢という花が
Flowers of countless dreams
つぼみのまま咲くのを待ってる
wait in bud to blossom.
雨の中でも風の中でも 大事大事に育ててきた
Nurtured with care through rain and wind,
しぼみそうになるときも たくさん元気をもらえる根っこ
Roots that give me plenty of energy when I'm about to wilt,
だからまだぜんぜん 枯れたりしない
So they won't wither away at all.
想いは太陽の光、浴びて
Bathed in the sunlight,
鮮やかに輝くよ
feelings shine brightly,
空を全部覆うほど
covering the entire sky.
めいっぱい、この両手広げて、さあ
Opening both hands to the fullest, come on,
みんながいれば 何でもできるよ！
With everyone here, anything is possible!
想いは真っ直ぐ、伸びていけ
Feelings stretch straight ahead,
あの空に届くように
reaching up to that sky.
もう怖いものなんかない
With nothing more to fear,
めいっぱい咲かせるよ
I'll make it bloom in full,
みんなで咲かそう たくさんの花
Let's make countless flowers bloom together,
満開の桃の花
Peach blossoms in full bloom.
想いはまっすぐ、伸びていけ
Feelings stretch straight ahead,
あの空に届くように
reaching up to that sky.
もう怖いものなんかない
With nothing more to fear,
めいっぱい咲かせるよ
I'll make it bloom in full,
自分という名の大きな花
A great flower called myself,
満開の桃の花
A peach blossom in full bloom.
いくつもの夢という花が
Flowers of countless dreams
つぼみのまま咲くのを待ってる
wait in bud to blossom.
雨の中でも風の中でも 大事大事に育ててきた
Nurtured with care through rain and wind,
しぼみそうになるときも たくさん元気をもらえる根っこ
Roots that give me plenty of energy when I'm about to wilt,
だからまだぜんぜん 枯れたりしない
So they won't wither away at all.
想いは太陽の光、浴びて
Bathed in the sunlight,
鮮やかに輝くよ 空を全部覆うほど
feelings shine brightly, covering the sky.
めいっぱい、この両手広げて、さあ
Opening both hands to the fullest, come on,
みんながいれば 何でもできるよ！
With everyone here, anything is possible!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
というわけで、初披露の曲「モモノネ」を聴いていただきました！
And that was the premiere performance of my song "Momonone"!
いかがでしたでしょうか？
How was it?
この曲、なんとみんな！なんとまあ詳細知りたいでしょ？
You all want to know the details of this song, right?
というわけで、この曲の詳細と、ネネからの告知を二つ紹介するためにステージを移動していきたいと思いますので
So, to introduce the details and two announcements, I'll be moving to the stage...
ちょっとね、長めなんだけど、みんな今日もね、あのスタッフさんたちがねこを使って生劇作ってくれましたので
It's a bit long, but the staff put together a live sketch using cats today, so please enjoy watching!
はーい、ということで先ほどお聞きいただきました曲の詳細を発表したいと思います。
Hi everyone, so I'd like to announce the details of the song you just heard!
どんっ！
Ta-da!
桃鈴ねね 3rdシングル 「モモネ」、
Momosuzu Nene's 3rd single, "Momone,"
えー今日この日付が変わった0時0分から配信開始になります！いぇーい！
will be available for streaming starting right at midnight today! Yay!
なんと今回も作詞作曲編曲ヒゲドライバーさんにお願いをしました！ありがとうございます！
And once again, I asked Hige Driver-san to write, compose, and arrange it! Thank you so much!
そしてなんとね、今回もねねがジャケットのイラストを描いて、そしてこの「モモネ」にあったね、衣装を考えたくてすごい時間かけてこの
And what's more, this time Nene drew the jacket illustration herself, and I wanted an outfit that matched "Momone," so I spent a lot of time designing it.
ジャケットを描きました。そしてね、この「モモネ」っていう文字とこのなんか散らばってるマークもねねが今回考えました。もうすごい愛が溢れてるでしょ？
I drew the jacket. And I came up with the letters "Momone" and the scattered marks myself this time. It's overflowing with love, right?
どう？どうみんな？どうだった？この曲さ、みんな、ねねがこんな前半前半の息で歌ってるやつじゃなくて、ちゃんと聞いたの聞きたいでしょ？ちゃんとしたのは
How is it, everyone? How was it? This song, guys, you want to hear Nene singing properly instead of just gasping for breath in the first half, right? You want to hear the proper version.
あ、戻してもらって大丈夫です。
Oh, it's okay to switch it back.
よいしょ。ちゃんと聞いたの聞きたいでしょ？そんなみんなのために、22時15分からのプレミアム公開で、なんと
There we go. You want to hear the proper one, right? For all of you, in the premiere starting at 22:15, guess what?
桃鈴ねねのフルMV公開！
Momosuzu Nene's full MV will be premiered!
いぇーい！なんとMVのイラストを描いたのは誰なんだって？え、え、え、え？ねねだー！
Yay! Who do you think drew the MV illustration? Eh, eh, eh, eh? It was Nene!
ねねがね、もう自分のすごい1年の集大成、1年の締めくくり、1年の終焉を込めまして、
Nene put her heart into it as the culmination, conclusion, and finale of her amazing 1st year,
あの、すごい気合を入れて描きました。そして時間ない中で一生懸命動画を作ってくださったので、それをね、みんなにフルで見てもらいたくて、
Um, I drew it with all my might. And they worked so hard to make the video in such a short time, so I wanted everyone to see it in full,
22時15分からプレミア公開を撮ってます。よかったらそちらも遊びに来て、ねねのこの「モモネ」のね
so we're having a premiere at 22:15. If you'd like, please come check it out and experience Nene's "Momone" song together.
あの曲の良さを一緒に知っていただければと思います。なんとね、そのMVの歌詞？
I hope you can appreciate how great the song is. And you know, the lyrics in the MV?
なんか下にさ歌詞が出るじゃん、なんかMVって。こう横とかに。そのMVに出てくる文字、全部ねね！
You know how lyrics appear at the bottom in MVs? Like on the sides. All the text appearing in that MV is by Nene!
もうイラストねね、歌ねね、文字ねね！ジャケットねね、動画は動画師さん。
Illustration by Nene, vocals by Nene, text by Nene! Jacket by Nene, video by the video editor.
もうすごい！愛込めちゃったのでよかったらみんなで見ましょう！ねねも放送終わったら遊びに行きます。すごいでしょう？
It's amazing! I put so much love into it, so let's all watch it together! Nene will go hang out there after the broadcast ends too. Isn't that amazing?
昨日のお便りからもお知らせがあったと思うんですけど、ねねからも1周年を記念したグッズを売ってます。
I think there were announcements in yesterday's letters too, but Nene is also selling 1st anniversary goods.
すごいね、リクエストが多かったあれと、あれが出ますので、よかったらね、今から詳細発表するんでみんなドキドキワクワクで見てください！というわけで、
There are items with a lot of requests coming out, so I'll announce the details right now, please look forward to it with excitement! So,
桃鈴ねね1周年記念のグッズ、こちらどーん！活動1周年記念、
Momosuzu Nene's 1st anniversary goods, here they are, ta-da! For the 1st anniversary of activities,
桃鈴ねねのグッズはなんと記念ボイスが2種類、記念グッズが2種類、え、なんとねんがんの抱き枕と、ねっことのぬいぐるみでーす！いぇーい！
Momosuzu Nene's goods include 2 types of commemorative voice packs, 2 types of commemorative goods, and um, amazingly, our long-awaited hug pillow and Neko plushie! Yay!
そしてフルセットには、ねねの、えっと手描きのねメッセージ入りの書き下ろしのポストカードが付きます。
And for the full set, Nene's, um, hand-written message-included newly drawn postcard is included.
ついたと思います。
I think we're connected.
ほら、こんな感じで。
Look, something like this.
すごい、みんな見たいでしょ？もっとじっくり見たいでしょ？
Isn't it amazing? You all want to see it, right? You want to look closer, right?
ってことで、
So,
まず抱き枕カバー、こちら！
first, the body pillow cover, here it is!
見て！抱き枕カバー！
Look! The body pillow cover!
もうね、ざんまい、今のホロライブにできる限界のえっちで書いてくださいって発注した結果こうなりました。
I ordered it saying, "Please draw it as lewdly as possible within the limits of what Hololive can do today," and this is the result.
なかなかね、見れないねねが上着をちゃんと閉めてる姿と、
It's quite rare to see Nene properly buttoning up her jacket,
もうボロンボロンのビヨンビヨンに全部出でる姿を書いてもらいました。
and also her bursting out completely loose and bouncy in all her glory.
よかったらこのあと出る詳細ページでご確認ください。
If you'd like, please check the details page coming up soon.
概要欄にあるのかな？
Is it in the description?
マネちゃん概要欄、
Mane-chan, the description—
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you!
概要欄にあります、よかったら見てください。
It's in the description, please go take a look.
そして次、
And next,
こちら！ねっこのぬいぐるみ！
this one! Neko's plushie!
これもうみんな、すごい可愛い！
This is just so cute, everyone!
ねねこれ、サンプルで1個もらったんだけど、
I got one as a sample,
1個じゃちょっと足りない！部屋に3つくらい置きたい！
but one isn't quite enough! I want to put like three in my room!
もうこれ絶対みんな手に入れてほしい！ねねこれ、これだけでもいいからこれだけでもいいから、
I really want everyone to get this! Nene wants everyone to get this, even if it's just this,
もうすごい、すごい可愛くなっちゃったから！ねっこのぬいぐるみ、ざんまむね、ねっこのぬいぐるみ欲しいやん、なあって言ってて
it got so, so cute! I was saying, "I want Neko's plushie so badly,"
形にしちゃいました！
and made it a reality!
そして次、フルセットの購入特典で、
And next, as a full set purchase bonus,
ねねのかきおろしのポストカード、そしてメッセージはまだ秘密のメッセージ入りのポストカードがついてきます！
you get a post card with Nene's new illustration, and a postcard with a secret message!
このイラストはもう今回限定なので、ねねの自分のイラストをグッズにするのってすごい夢なんだけど、
This illustration is exclusive to this time, and turning my own illustration into merchandise is a huge dream of mine,
まずここでね、ポストカードにしてもらって夢1個かなえちゃいましたね！
so getting it made into a postcard here made one of my dreams come true!
よかったらこちらも絶対絶対手に入れてね！ねねといつまでも一緒だよお！
If you'd like, please make sure to get this too! Nene will be with you forever!
はあ、というわけで、プレミアム公開と新曲とグッズのお知らせでした！
Ha, so that was the premium release, new song, and merchandise announcement!
というわけで、今日はこれで終わりになってしまいます！みんな、2年目のねねもよろしくね！というわけでばいばい！
So, today ends here! Everyone, please support Nene in her second year too! So bye-bye!
ねねねねねねねね！大爆走！
Nenenenenenenenenene! Great runaway!
作詞作曲ヒゲドライバー
Lyrics & Music: Hige Driver
グッズも新曲もチェックよろしくお願いします！
Please check out the merchandise and the new song too!
異世界から来ましたアイドル志望の新参VTuber！
A newbie VTuber aspiring to be an idol, coming from another world!
たまにはかーかるくいきましょう！
Anyway, let's take it easy!
ちょっと暗い気持ちだって全部忘れちゃって
Forget all those gloomy feelings
一歩ずつだって進んだっていい
Step by step, moving forward is fine
って感じでいこうぜ！
Let's go with that vibe!
あきらめの悪さは長所だよね！
Stubbornness is a strong point, right?
こんなこともあるけど、
There are things like this,
悔しいこともあるけど、
and frustrating things too,
大丈夫！今日もしっかりおめかしして、
but it's okay! Today too, all dressed up nicely,
いつかは君とせーのでスーパーねねっち！
someday with you, ready, set, Super Nenetch!
食い込んできてね！
Keep pushing through!
手を抜くならこそ全力で行こう！
Let's go all out when taking a break!
思いっきりやればなんとかなる今日を
Live today to the fullest and things will work out,
ぼちぼちでいい、少しずつでいい、ただ駆け抜けていこうよ！
Slowly is fine, a little at a time is fine, let's just run through it!
大爆走！
Great runaway!
みんなありがとう！アイノテありがとう！みんなコメント見えてるよ！
Thank you everyone! Thank you for the call-and-response! I see all your comments!
なななな な 「な」じゃなくて
Not na, nana-na-na-na,
にににに に 「に」じゃなくて
not ni, nini-ni-ni-ni,
ぬぬぬぬ ぬ 「ぬ」じゃなくて
not nu, nunu-nu-nu-nu,
のののの の 「の」じゃなくて
not no, nono-no-no-no,
……「ね」！
...Ne!
（ねね！）
(Nene!)
（よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ！）
(Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho, yoisho!)
（ねね！）
Nene!
（よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ！）
(Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho, yoisho!)
こんねね～！（こんねね～！）
Hello, Nene! (Hello, Nene!)
ホロライブ5期生
Hololive 5th Generation,
オレンジ担当
Orange representative,
桃鈴ねねです！（ねねちー！）
Momosuzu Nene! (Nenechi!)
異世界から来ました
I came from another world,
アイドル志望の
an aspiring idol,
新人VTuber（なんだって！？）
a rookie VTuber! (Wait, what!?)
ま、とにかくいきいきましょう！
Well, anyway, let's stay bright and cheerful!
ちょっとくらい緊張したって 滑ったって
Even if I'm a bit nervous or slip up,
「うおー！」って感じでいこう（うおー！）
shout "Oh!" (Oh!)
「どりゃあ！」っていっていこう（どりゃあ！）
and dive right in with "Toryaa!" (Toryaa!)
あきらめの悪さは長所だよね？
Never giving up is my strong suit, you know!
ね ねねね ね ねねね ね（ね！）
Ne, nenene, nenene, nenene, nene! (Ne!)
「はぁ～ん」なこともあるけど
Sometimes there are moments of "Haa~n"
悔しいこともあるけど大丈夫！
and regrets too, but it'll be alright!
今日もしっかりと、めかめかして
Today too, with a solid, sparkly shine,
いつかはきっと
someday I'll surely be...
「すーぱーねねちー！」
"Super Nenechi!"
ついてきてね
Come follow me!
ねねねね ねねね ねねねね ねねねね（ね！）
Ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne-ne-ne, ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne-ne-ne (Ne!)
ねねねね ねね（ね！）
Ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne-ne (Ne!)
ねねねね ね（ね！）
Ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne (Ne!)
ねねねね ねねねね（ねね！）
Ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne-ne-ne (Ne!)
って、全力で行こう！
Let's go with all our might!
そん で 全開で行こう！
Yep, let's go full throttle!
思い切りやればなんとかなるよ
If you give it your all, things will work out!
ポンコツだっていい（よいしょ！）
Being a bit clumsy is fine! (Yoisho!)
誤字ったっていい（よいしょ！）
Making typos is fine! (Yoisho!)
ただ駆け抜けていこうね
Let's just keep on running through!
（ね！ね！ね！ね！）
(Ne! Ne! Ne! Ne!)
大爆走
The Nene-Nene-Nene Sprint!
（ねね！）
(Ne!)
（よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ！）
(Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho, yoisho!)
（ねね！）
(Nene!)
（よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ！）
(Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho, yoisho!)
野菜ジュースと炭酸とお菓子、
Vegetable juice, carbonated drinks, and sweets—
そろえて準備OK！
got them all ready, OK!
でも朝は苦手（だね！）
But mornings are tough, (Right!)
夜も苦手（だね！）
nights are tough too, (Right!)
やっぱり睡眠って、大事だよね？
Sleep really is important, huh?
ね ねねね ね ねねね ね（ね！）
Ne, ne, nene, ne, nene, ne, nene (Ne!)
たくさんの人に、愛されたい！
I want to be loved by so many people!
ちゅちゅちゅ（ちゅちゅちゅ）
Chu-chu-chu! (Chu-chu-chu!)
大好きなみんなに、愛されたい！
Loved by everyone I love!
ちゅちゅちゅ（ちゅちゅちゅ）
Chu-chu-chu! (Chu-chu-chu!)
そうしたら なるんだ
And then I become...
「はいぱーねねちー！」
"Hyper Nenechi!"
やってっ
Let's go for it!
ねねねね ねねね ねねねね ねねねね（ね！）
Ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne-ne-ne, ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne-ne-ne (Ne!)
ねねねね ねね（ね！）
Ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne-ne (Ne!)
ねねねね ね（ね！）
Ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne (Ne!)
ねねねね ねねねね（ねね！）
Ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne-ne-ne (Ne!)
って、全力で行こう！
And go at full power!
そん で 全開で行こう！
Yep, let's go full throttle!
歌は誰にも負けたじたくないんだ
I don't want to lose to anyone in singing,
大きな声を（よいしょ！）
so with a loud voice— (Yoisho!)
あ、その前に（よいしょ！）
Oh, wait, before that— (Yoisho!)
ちょっとトイレ行ってくるね～
I'm gonna go to the restroom real quick!
（restroom time!!!）
(Restroom time!)
（ねね！）
(Nene!)
（よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ！）
(Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho, yoisho!)
（ねね！）
(Nene!)
（よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ！）
(Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho, yoisho!)
なななな な 「な」じゃなくて
Not na, nana-na-na-na,
にににに に 「に」じゃなくて
not ni, nini-ni-ni-ni,
ぬぬぬぬ ぬ 「ぬ」じゃなくて
not nu, nunu-nu-nu-nu,
のののの の 「の」じゃなくて
not no, nono-no-no-no,
ただいま～！
I'm back!
最後に
And finally...
ねねねね ねねね ねねねね ねねねね（ね！）
Ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne-ne-ne, ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne-ne-ne (Ne!)
ねねねね ねね（ね！）
Ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne-ne (Ne!)
ねねねね ね（ね！）
Ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne (Ne!)
ねねねね ねねねね（ねね！）
Ne-ne-ne-ne ne-ne-ne-ne (Ne!)
って、全力で行こう！
Let's go with all our might!
そん で 全開で行こう！
Yep, let's go full throttle!
思い切りやればなんとかなるよ
If you give it your all, things will work out!
五時立て一、五時立て一
Pushing through with all my might,
ただかせるげていこうよね
just tackling it head-on!
（ね！ね！ね！ね！）
(Ne! Ne! Ne! Ne!)
大爆走
The Nene-Nene-Nene Sprint!
（ねね！）
(Ne!)
（よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ！）
(Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho, yoisho!)
（ねね！）
(Nene!)
（よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ よいしょ！）
(Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho, yoisho!)
それじゃ本当にまたねね！
Then it'll really be Nene again!
バイバーーーイ
Bye-bye!